hallmark.com 2018-05-09

# Privacy & Security | Hallmark

## Hallmark's Privacy Statement

Hallmark and its family of companies value you and respect your privacy. It has always been Hallmark's firm policy to conduct business with scrupulous respect for the law. We collect information to support our relationship with you, improve our product offering and to communicate about products, services, and promotions. Hallmark recognizes that we must maintain and use information responsibly. We may disclose information to companies that work with us and assist us with providing services to you. In addition, Hallmark Gold Crown retailers receive information to communicate with you and improve your shopping experience. Occasionally, Hallmark.com uses personal consumer information to market the products and services of Hallmark Cards, Inc., its subsidiaries; and on a limited basis, we may share your contact information with trusted business partners so that they may market their products and services to you. You can always find the most recent version of our privacy policy on this page. 

  * Effective Date: 9/23/02
  * Last Updated: 04/16/18

## What information does Hallmark collect and why?

We collect information you provide when you place an order, register with us, send an ecard, send us an email or call us, enter a sweepstakes or enroll in a club or service. This information may include: 

  * Your name
  * Your mailing address
  * Your email address
  * Your phone number
  * Your credit card number
  * Your Crown Rewards card
  * Your Facebook Connect sign-in information

## Who does Hallmark share information with?

We share personal customer information with our agents, representatives, trusted service providers, and contractors for limited purposes. Those purposes may be fulfilling customer orders; offering products and services in connection with our website; customer service; giving access to our partners' sites; or finishing credit card transactions. These third parties are not allowed to use this information. They can only fulfill orders and service your questions.

From time to time, we may share the contact information of our customers with carefully picked and trustworthy third parties so the third parties can promote their products and services. You can opt out from our sharing of your information for this particular purpose anytime by changing the preferences of your account at Hallmark.com. You can also call 1-800-HALLMARK and ask to be taken off our business partner promotions listing. Hallmark does not share email information.

We may put the information you give us online at Hallmark.com with information you've given at Hallmark Gold Crown retail stores. We do this with the hope of making your shopping experience more enjoyable.

If you log in through Facebook Connect, information you provide to us may be shared with Facebook.

Hallmark reserves the right to work with law enforcement officials in the investigation of any possible unlawful activities of our customers related to electronic communication transmitted on our site. Hallmark will have no legal responsibilities for such disclosures. We may also give information to other groups for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. We may share grouped demographic and statistical information with our other partners. No personal information that can identify any individual person is shown in that disclosure.

## Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as S.B. 27, allows individual customers who have provided their personal information to Hallmark to request information about our disclosures of certain categories of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us in one of the following ways: send a letter to Hallmark Cards Consumer Care; P.O. Box 419034; Kansas City, MO 64141; or call 1-800-HALLMARK. Within thirty days of receiving such a request, we will provide a list of the categories of personal information disclosed to third parties for third party direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding year, along with the names and addresses of these third parties. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted to locations other than those specified above.

## How does Hallmark handle contest and survey responses?

Every now and then, Hallmark or its research partners will invite customers to take part in contests and surveys. The information we collect from these contests and surveys may be matched with individual customer accounts and used by Hallmark to improve your overall customer experience. The information will only be shared with third parties in grouped form.

## What if I am an affiliate partner?

If you sign up to be a Hallmark.com affiliate partner, you will be led to a third-party website. This website manages the affiliate process. The third party is not allowed to use information they get for anything other than running the affiliate process.

## What technical devices and processes does Hallmark.com use to collect information about me?

Our technology lets us identify what type of browser you are using, the website from which you enter Hallmark.com and the pages you view as you tour our site. This technology helps us compile grouped statistics about online guests and their use of Hallmark.com. These statistics allow us to improve the design and content of our site to better serve your needs. Hallmark.com uses cookies to provide features like auto-login and to determine when customers have visited our site before. If your browser is set to reject cookies, we cannot make auto-login available to you. Auto-login includes giving you access to your address book without first entering your Hallmark.com user name and password.

Analytics and performance cookies help analyze how you and other users use our Services. In addition to tracking technologies that we place, other companies may also set their own cookies or similar tools when you use the services. This includes third-party analytics services (such as Google Analytics), as well as third parties that deliver content or offers. We use that information only to improve our Services. The information generated by the analytics and performance cookies about your use of services are transmitted to analytics services that may also transfer information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process analytics Information on their behalf. Each analytics service's ability to use and share analytics Information is restricted by such analytics services' terms of use agreement and privacy policy. By using our Services, you consent to the processing of information about you by analytics services in the manner and for the purposes set forth above.

We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with online advertising from third party ad servers. Our third party ad servers may deliver advertisements tailored to your interests. To opt out of our cookies used for this online advertising, please [click here](http://dtmc.hallmark.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=2031&cname=Hallmark&cmagic=88ef51&clogo=2031.png&loc=us&lang=en-us). You may also be able to adjust your privacy and advertising settings to limit interest-based advertising, but Hallmark cannot guarantee and does not control the effectiveness of browser-based tools for managing cookies. We encourage you to view the privacy policy of advertisers and ad services to learn more about their cookies and other technologies.

Advertising cookies are cookies we place on our Services so that third parties (such as LiveRamp and Facebook Custom Audiences) can identify users, group them with other users with similar interests, and deliver to you and them interest-based content and advertisements. The information collected about you may also be used to track your location, activity and serve interest-based content and advertisements across multiple websites, apps, and across multiple devices. We may share information about you with our advertising partners such as your name, postal address, email, or other identifier, which is turned into hashed or obfuscated data used only to match the advertising cookie to other non-personally identifiable points. Our advertising cookie partners may also may collect information directly from your device, such as your IP address, device ID, and information about your browser or operating system; may combine our non-personal information about you with information from other sources; and may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. To opt-out of third party cookies, please go to <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>.  Hallmark also participates in the Adobe Marketing Cloud Device Co-op to better understand how you use our website and apps across your various devices, and to deliver tailored promotions. To learn more go to [https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com](https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com/).

We use "Pixel Tags" (also referred to as clear .gifs, web beacons, or web bugs), which are tiny graphic images, each with a unique identifier, that are similar to cookies and are used to track online movements of users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, pixel tags are embedded invisibly in websites and emails and can let us know when they have been downloaded and viewed. We may use such information from Pixel Tags to reduce or eliminate messages sent to a user.

Like most websites, the servers that serve our website automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We log IP addresses and we use them to track things like the number of people that visit our website.

## Does Hallmark use third parties?

Hallmark uses OAS to procure, serve and/or facilitate serving advertisements. OAS may access, collect, obtain and use non-personally identifiable information ("Non-PII") about users visits by use of tracking pixels, cookies or other visitor identification technology that collects anonymous traffic data to procure and/or provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to users. To learn more about OAS' information collection and protection practices, please visit http://www.247realmedia.com/EN-US/privacy-policy.html.

Additionally, Hallmark uses the services of AOL, MSN, DART, Yahoo! and Google for the serving of ads, promotions and other marketing messages. To do this, AOL, MSN, DART, Yahoo! and Google collect anonymous data from this site through the use of cookies. This anonymous data is also used to develop aggregate reports on our customer's reactions to ad campaigns and to learn more about our general audience so we may provide only the most relevant offers and promotions.

To learn more about AOL, MSN, DART, Yahoo! and Google, including your ability to opt out of the AOL, MSN, DART, Yahoo! and Google systems, go to  

  * <http://about.aol.com/aolnetwork/aol_pp>,
  * <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>,
  * <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx>,
  * <http://privacy.yahoo.com/privacy/us/pixels/details.html>, or

## How do I access and change my email contact preferences?

When you make a Hallmark.com account, your contact preferences automatically shows that you want to get promotional information from Hallmark about news on Hallmark products, services, and events. It also indicates that you would like to be told about special offers, products and free samples from Hallmark partners.

If you do not want to be contacted by Hallmark for promotional purposes, you may change your preferences at anytime. Be sure you are signed in to your Hallmark.com account. Hover on the Hi statement in the purple bar. Select Profile and click on the Settings link at right of the page. A Communication Preferences box will appear. Uncheck the box next to the statement "Hallmark and its companies can contact me about special offers and promotions."

## How do I access and change my personal information?

You can change or delete your personal information anytime. Sign in to your Hallmark.com account. Hover on the Hi statement in the purple bar. Select Profile and click on the Edit button at right of the page. You can update any of your personal information by choosing what information you would like to update. For example, your address book or reminder service can be updated if you choose to do so. You will then be taken to where you can change or submit new information.

## How secure is the information that I give to Hallmark?

What technology does Hallmark.com use to ensure the security of credit card transactions?

We seek high standards in credit card security to better protect the information you give us when you shop on Hallmark.com. Our servers use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) to protect storage and transference of your data from wrongful parties. We also use a digital secure server ID to give you more security when you are on the Internet.

## How secure is my Hallmark.com account information?

To protect your account information, Hallmark.com asks that you enter a valid user name and password before buying anything using your account information. We may also collect personal information to make purchasing easier for you in the future. For example, if you give us permission to store your billing information, you won't have to fill out the shipping and billing address each time you make a purchase on our site.

Hallmark also has security measures to protect the loss, misuse, and change of your information. Only certain employees and agents of Hallmark.com have access to this information. This information is only used for completing your order.

## Are my ecard messages confidential?

Your ecard messages are always kept confidential and secure. Ecards will only be accessed when it is necessary to complete your order. Hallmark reserves the right to work with law enforcement officials in the investigation of possible unlawful activities of our customers related to electronic communication transmitted on our site. Hallmark will have no legal responsibility for such disclosures.

## Are my personal messages private when I personalize Hallmark cards and ecards?

When you add a personal message to your order, it is secured by Hallmark. For order fulfillment, an order-processing representative may view your message. Once again, third parties are not allowed to use this information. They can only fulfill orders and service your questions.

## Address Book

Hallmark.com gives you the chance to create an online address book to keep track of important addresses once you have made a user account. Address book information is highly confidential. That information will not be used for Hallmark, or third party promotions.

## Reminder Notifications

Once you have made a user account, Hallmark.com lets you set reminders for important holidays and events. Your requested reminders will often include links to our site for products and other content that you may find to be relevant to you. Reminder notification information is highly confidential and will not be shared with third parties.

## Does Hallmark.com ensure the security and privacy practices of other sites it links to?

While we carefully select the websites we link to, we are not at fault for the privacy practices or content of these websites. You are under the privacy policy of the operator of that site when you give personal information to them, not the Hallmark privacy policy. Please read the policy of that site before sharing any information.

## How will I know when Hallmark changes its privacy policy?

Our privacy policy is regularly reviewed to make sure we continue to serve the privacy interests and needs of our customers. If we decide to change our privacy policy in whole or in part, we will inform you by posting a notice on our website. Those changes will go into effect on the date posted in the notice. The new policy will apply to all current and past users of our website, and will replace any prior policies that are inconsistent. You should check our website occasionally for more information on how we use the data we collect.

## How do I contact Hallmark if I still have questions?

You may contact us by using the "Contact Us" links in our "Customer Service" area. This information is used to respond directly to your questions or comments. We may also file your comments and share them with our customer care team to improve our service in the future. Your personal information will only be shared with third parties in the event that we need to follow up with specific order-related questions or comments. The third parties will not use your information for promotions or any other purposes.

If you still have questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please write us at:

Hallmark Cards Consumer Care  
P.O. Box 419034  
Kansas City, MO 64141
